hello anyone in there hello are you
getting from the door anytime hello
no are you gonna open this door because
it's fairly urgent I'll just open the
door that's too aggressive hello friend
why not open the door hmm could be
Spanish could be Spanish hola amico
abre la puerta donde esta no fine no for
absolutely fine it's not like I don't
have you know 10,000 other test subjects
begging me to help them escape you know
it's not like this place is about to
explode
all right look okay I'll be honest
you're the last test subject left and if
you don't help me we're both gonna die
all right if you want to say it there
you go you've got it out of me
all right dead dose where teh god open
the door hello ha I knew someone was
alive in here ah God God you looked good
looking good actually are you okay are
you don't answer that I'm actually sure
you're fine there's plenty of time for
you to recover just take it slow
stay calm stay calm prepare it's always
saying prepare it's all fine alright
don't move I'm gonna get us out of here
oh you might want to hang on to
something
word of advice up to you you're right
down there can you hear me hello most
test subjects do experience some
cognitive deterioration after a few
months in suspension now you've been
under for quite a lot longer and it's
not out of the question that you might
have a very minor case of serious brain
damage but don't be alarmed
alright although if you do if you do
feel alarm try to hold onto that feeling
because that is the proper reaction to
being told that you've got brain damage
do you understand what I'm saying that's
all what does any of this make any sense
just tell me just say yes okay what
you're doing there is jumping you just
you just jumped but never mind
say Apple Apple simple word Apple just
say Apple classic very simple a double
ple just say Apple easy word isn't it
Apple how would you use it in a sentence
mmm this apples crunchy you might say
and I'm not even asking you for the
whole sentence just the word Apple okay
you know what that's close enough just
hold tight okay look I wasn't gonna
mention this to you but I'm in pretty
hot water
how you doing down there he's still
holding on the reserve power ran out so
of course the whole relaxation center
stops waking up the bloody test subjects
hold on this is a bit tricky and of
course nobody tells me anything know
what you tell me anything why should I
be kept informed you know about the life
functions of the 10000 bloody test
subjects I'm supposed to be in charge of
all rights cloaks can you see I'm not
gonna make it through have I got enough
space just just go get through here okay
I just got concentrate and whose fault
do you think it's gonna be when the
management comes down here and finds
10000 flippin vegetables all right see
now I hate that one I hate that one okay
listen we should get our stories
straight all right if anyone asks and no
one's gonna ask don't worry but if
anyone asks tell them as far as you know
the last time you checked everyone
looked pretty much alive all right not
dead okay almost there on the other side
of that wall is one of the old testing
tracks there's a piece of equipment in
there that we're gonna need to get out
of here I think this is a docking
station get ready
good news that is not a docking station
so there's one mystery solved I'm going
to attempt a manual override on this
wall could get a bit technical hold on
almost there
remember you're looking for a gun that
makes holes not bullet holes but don't
worry you'll figure out seriously do
hold on this time well there we go now
I'll be honest you are probably in no
fit state to run this particular type of
cognitive gauntlet but at least you're a
good jumper so you got that got the
jumping on your side just do your best
and I'll meet you up ahead all right off
you go go on just March on through that
hole yeah it's all right go ahead I know
I know I have painted quite a grim
picture of your chances but if you
simply stand here we will both surely
die so once again just move along one
small step and everything on you go your
destinations probably not going to come
and meet us here is it so go on that's
the spirit good luck hey you made it
there should be a portal device on that
podium over there I can't see it though
maybe it fell off don't go
great look it's all right Nicole just
have a look about now that's right over
by the podium yeah
if you just okay just stand by the
podium and just look up that's it yeah
that's it yeah oh hello can you see the
portal gun also are you alive that's
important you have asked that first um
do you know what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
work on the assumption that you're still
alive and I'm just gonna wait for you up
ahead I'll wait I'll wait one hour then
I'll come back and assuming I can locate
your dead body I'll bury you all right
brilliant go team see you in an hour
hopefully if you're not dead
Hey hi I'm up here Oh brilliant you did
find a portal gun of the deal what it
just goes to show people with brain
damage are the real heroes in the end
aren't they at the end of the day brave
pop a portal on that wall behind me
there and I'll meet you on the other
side of the room just pop a portal right
behind me there and come on through to
the other side pop a pill portal just
there all right behind me and come on
through right by me all right let me
explain again pop a portal behind me all
right and come on through pop a portal
behind me on the wall come on through
come on through come on through to the
other side come on through okay listen
let me lay something on you here is
pretty heavy they told me never never
ever to disengage myself from my
management rail or I would die but we're
out of options here so get ready to
catch me all right on the off chance
that I'm not dead the moment I pop off
this thing on 3 ready 1 2 3 that's high
it's what it's too high isn't it really
that all right going on 3 just gives you
too much time to think about it let's go
on one this time okay ready
what gasps we guess we catch me catch me
ow ow I'm not dead I'm not dead
I can't move there that's the problem
there are you still you still there
could you pick me up do you think if you
are there hello can you pick me up
please
sorry are you still there could you pick
could you pick me up if you are there
would you mind giving me a little bit of
help just picking me up look look down
where I why where am I on the floor
needing you how
the whole time all the time needing a
help still here on the floor waiting to
be picked up look tank where is that
down there talking it's me
down on the floor needing you to pick me
up I spy with my little eye something
that starts with F do you give up
it was the floor lying down on the floor
is where I am needing you to pick me up
don't want to hassle you you sure you're
busy but still here on the floor waiting
to be picked up I spy with my little eye
something that starts with an A give up
also the floor was the answer that time
same as before still on the floor what
do you do you just have your little 5
minutes to yourself fair enough
you've had a rough time you've been
asleep for who knows how long you got
the massive brain damage and you having
a little rest but now get yourself up
and pick me up
Oh brilliant thank you great plug me
into that stick on the wall over there
yeah and I'll show you something you'll
be impressed by this don't just Jeremy
in over there right on that stick over
there just put me right on it it is
tricky it is tricky but just plug me in
please plug me into that stick on the
wall over there I'll show you something
it does sound rude I'm not gonna lie to
you it does sound rude it's not put me
right on it stick me in yeah I can't do
if you're watching seriously I'm not I'm
not joking could you just turn around
for a second ok I can't do it if you're
watching I can't do if you're watching
if you just turn around what's that
behind you it's only a robot a bloody
stick a different one
alright can't do it if you're if you're
leering at me
it's creepy ok listen I can't do it with
you watching I know it seems pathetic
given what we've been through but just
turn right please all right you can turn
right now BAM secret panel but I opened
while your back was turned
pick me up let's get out of here pick
would you pick me up would you pick me
up hey pick me up pick me up don't
forget to pick me up might want to just
pick me up
Oh oh no don't leave me behind do pick
me up if you would just pick me up take
me with you Oh remember when you pick me
up five seconds ago that was amazing
do it again pick me up again let's do it
again pick me up again and off we go
look this no rail to tell us where to go
oh this is brilliant you go ever we want
just hold on there where are we going
seriously hey let me just get my
bearings um
just follow the rail actually Oh No yes
he'll stop don't be content whatever you
do no thanks we're good
free sure keep moving keep moving
probable to bring you up to speed on
something right now in order to escape
we're gonna have to go through her
chamber and she will probably kill us if
she's awake if you want to just call it
quits
we could just sit here forever that's an
option option a sit here do nothing
option B go through there and if she's
alive she will most certainly kill us so
if you've got any reservations
whatsoever about this plan now would be
a tremendous time to voice them right
now in case you thought to yourself I've
missed the window of time to voice no
reservations still open okay I'm gonna
lay my cards on the table I don't want
to do it I don't want to go in there
don't go in to geez off she's off don't
panic over she's off Oh fine oh we go
there she is
what a nasty piece of work she was
honestly like a pop Romania do you know
who ended up her do you know who ended
up taking her down in the end you're
gonna believe this a human I know I know
I wouldn't believe it either
probably this human escaped and nobody's
seen him since the sort of long hunk of
time where absolutely nothing happened
and then there's also scape you know so
that's pretty much the whole story
you're up to speed
don't touch anything okay down these
stairs okay down those stairs please
jump this actually look at it that is
quite that's quite a distance isn't it
okay you know what
go ahead and jump you've got you've got
braces on your legs so you're all set
although no braces on your arms though
so you're gonna have to rely on the old
human strength to keep a grip on the
device and by extension me so do do
really make sure you keep a grip on me
also a note no braces on your spine
either so so don't land on that or your
head no braces there that could that
could split like a melon from this
height so do definitely focus on landing
with your legs great question have you
been working out cuz I'm gonna stairs no
evidence of it you know I'm not I'm not
like just a plastic cup we will be
landing with some force so a bit of bit
of grip is using grip classic grip right
let's go jump what's the worst that
could happen
ah I just thought about the worst thing
that could happen that oh I just thought
something even worse better plan a new
plan no imagining of any potential
outcomes whatsoever okay just just jump
just jump into the into the abyss
and see what happens oh I still there is
still in my head Oh still held still
being held you think that's a great job
you've applied the grip we're all fine
that's tremendous yeah I just sorry I
just looked down I do not recommend it
ah I've just done it again I just now
realize that I used to rely on my
management rail to not fall into
bottomless pits in a way you're my rail
now and you can't fall into a bottomless
pit and her rambling now out of fear but
here's the point don't get too close to
the edge this is the main breaker room
let's go in look for a switch that says
escape pod all right don't touch
anything else no issues anything else
don't touch anything else
don't even look anything else just well
obviously gonna look at everything else
to find the escape pod but as soon as
you look this I mean it doesn't say
escape pod look at something else look
at the next thing alright but don't
touch anything else or look anything
well look at other things but don't you
understand
can you see anywhere I can't see
anywhere tell you what plug me in and
I'll turn the lights on let there be
light
that's God is quoting God oh look at
that it's turning ominous but probably
fine long as it doesn't start in there
moving up now escape by ski pod it's
moving up okay don't worry don't worry
I've got it I've got it I've got it
this should slow it down no makes it go
faster oh okay don't panic
all right stop panicking I can I can
still stop this oh there's a there's a
password okay it's fine I'll just I'll
just hack it not a problem
ay ay ay ay ay ay
okay ay ay ay ay ay si no wait did I do
beat your pen start writing these down
I'd okay okay okay listen all right new
plan act natural natural we've done
nothing wrong hello you know her you did
what okay what happened right I was just
lying there
you thought I was done bird right
couldn't believe it either
and then the bird I found some bird eggs
up here just drops me to the door
mechanism shut it right down like ah
bird bird bird bird okay that's probably
the bird in it that laid the eggs livid
okay look the point is we're gonna break
out of here alright very soon I promise
I promise I just have to figure out how
to break us out of here here she comes
keep tape just keep testing remember you
never saw me never saw me hey how's it
going I talked my way onto the old
nanobot work crew rebuilding this shelf
they are really small I know Jerry no
I'm on a break mate Wow
just hang in there for five more T's
what Jerry you can't fire me for that
yes Jerry
or maybe you're prejudiced work site
should have accommodated a nanobot of my
size thanks for the hate crime Jer see
you in court mate anyway look just hang
in there for five more chambers hey
buddy
I'm speaking in an accent that is beyond
her range of hearing I know I'm early
but we have to go right now what
casually toward my position and we'll go
shut her down but I don't need to do the
voice run run come on come on come on
keep moving just keep moving run for
goodness sake
Coco Coco Ron come on I'm closing the
doors okay quick recap we are escaping
all right that's what's happening now
we're escaping so you're doing great
just keep running
quick worried about the future plans
that I've got in store we're gonna shut
down her turret production-line all
right turn offer a neurotoxin and then
confront her again though for the moment
right Oh what come how super does she
think we are oh come on come on yeah we
have to get you out of there can you can
you get out what's going on in there
try to make your way back out here I
hear it gunfire it's a bit like this but
I look out for gunfire probably doesn't
help at this point but I have at least
tried you're okay
great come on turrets there's the exit
we're almost out of here she's bringing
the whole place down hurry hurry this
way hurry this way get in the lift get
in the lift we've made it we made it we
made it we made it I'll meet you on the
other side ah brilliant you made it
through well then okay follow me we've
still got work to do
at least she can't touch us back here
what's happening hmm okay okay don't
move okay all right so I've got an idea
but it is bloody dangerous here we go
ah ah God they told me that if I ever
turn this flashlight on I would die they
told me that about everything I mean I
don't even know why they bother giving
me this stuff if they didn't want me to
use it it's pointless mad Oh start down
here isn't it they say that the old
caretaker of this place went absolutely
crazy chopped up his entire staff of
robots all of them robots they say at
night you can still hear the screams of
their replicas all of them functionally
indistinguishable from the originals no
memory of the incident nobody knows what
they're screaming about absolutely
terrifying though obviously not
paranormal in any meaningful way Oh
careful now try to jump across let's
keep moving the factory entrance must be
around here somewhere careful careful
wait careful let me light this jump for
you okay this looks dangerous I'll hold
the light steady Oh nicely done quick
this way here's an interesting story you
might like this
I almost got a job down here in
manufacturing but guess who the foreman
went with only an exact duplicate of
himself nepotism ended up giving me the
worst possible job tending to all the
smelly humans the the sorry that's no I
would say smelly just just attending to
the humans sorry about that I just
that's just slip taint of being
sensitive the smelly humans okay wait
let me like this path for you okay we
have to split up here for a moment
portal up to that passage and I'll see
you on the other side we've got to get
you out of that room can you reach that
wall back there okay there's another
wall over here oh that's how you humans
oh love them just then fading look it's
great and there you folklore wonderfully
colorful
right well I'm gonna take this rail down
the back way see you at the bomb good
luck be careful this is the turret
manufacturing wing just pass this is the
old neurotoxin production facility and
if we find a way to take them both
offline she's gonna be completely
helpless
which is ideal I'm pretty sure we're
going the right way pretty sure the
turret factory should be this way I
think oh just thought another great
thing about humans you invented us which
is great giving us the opportunity to
let you relax while we invented
everything else
could've done any of that without you
classy if you don't mind me saying are
you okay
are you alive down there if you're alive
can you say something jump around so I
know you're okay oh there you are they
are so I'm starting to get worried all
right let's try this again try to make
your way across the machinery let's keep
moving the factory entrance must be
around here somewhere okay this way no
no I'm sure it's this way I'm definitely
sure it's this way mmm okay let's try
this way could you hear that she's
really kicked this place into high gear
no no no no not that way here it is the
turret Factory entrance we made it ah
brilliant you made it through well done
follow me you're gonna love this almost
there there are only the turret control
center thank you very much yeah come on
look out the window it's good go on just
walk up the window okay it's interesting
I think you won't regret it I promise
just glass transparent smooth not gonna
hurt you have a look go on walk up to
the window take a look out see that
scanner right there right it's deciding
which turrets to keep and which to toss
and it's using that master turret there
as a template if we pull out the
template turret it'll shut down the
whole production line right hmm I'm
gonna have to hack the door so that we
can get at it
technical you'll need to turn right
while I do this turn around I'll only be
a second if you would mind God just just
turn right the way around so you're not
looking at me just turn around
could you would you turn around is that
possible would you mind putting your
back towards me so I can see only your
back and not your face done hacked okay
go on just pull that turret out what
that should do it
Oh hasn't done it right let's figure out
how to stop this turret line have you
got any ideas any ideas any ideas no no
me neither
are you are you still thinking or what's
happening tell you what here's a plan
let's just both continue contemplating
in absolute silence oh wait I got it
no I've got it oh I just had one idea
which is that I could pretend to her
that I've captured you and give you over
and she'll kill you but then I could go
on living so what's your view on that
there's no turret in it maybe the system
stores a backup image oh no hang on what
if we what if we gave it something else
to scam we could get one of the the crap
turrets we could put it in the scanner
see what happens yeah
go and catch one of the crap turrets and
bring it back wait where are you going
where are you going Oh have you got idea
okay well alright just do your idea and
then come straight back sorry what's
going on over there you know I'm
actually over here still thinking really
hard what what you have there
what are you Oh brilliant is / that's
brilliant
oh no you've got it you've got it yes
put him in there Oh let's see how this
place likes a crap turret it worked
if we're lucky she won't find out all
the turrets are crap until it's too late
classic okay keep your eye on the turret
line I'm gonna go and hack the door open
okay I'm about to start hacking it's a
little bit more complicated than it
looked from your side it should take
about 10 minutes keep one eye on the
door
these stores actually pretty complicated
you know when I mentioned 10 minutes a
little bit optimistic progress report
still pretty tricky progress report I
haven't really made any inroads I'm
still here I'm still working though i'm
forgotten about yeah oh good news never
mind what's happening your side anything
yeah oh how long's the door been opened
was there any sort of announcement
before I come looking like a buzzer or
an alarm some kind or like a hacker
alert not even you know fair enough the
important thing is it's open but just in
just mention in the future cough or
something all right now she can't use
her turrets so let's go and take care of
that neurotoxin generator as well bring
your daughter to work day that did not
end well and 40 potato batteries
embarrassing I mean I realize they're
children but still you know low-hanging
fruit all that Bailey science really did
baking soda volcano well you know at
least it's not a potato battery I'll
give it that but it's not terrifically
original is it you know I mean exactly
primary research even within the child
sciences I'm guessing this wasn't one of
the scientists children you know I don't
to be snobby but let's be honest it
Scott it's got manual labor written all
over it hasn't it no saying they're not
as good as the professionals you know
they're just they're just a lot dumber
connects growing right up into the
ceiling the whole place is probably
overrun with potatoes at this point
isn't it at least you won't starve them
I'm pretty sure we're going the right
way just to reassure you don't worry I'm
absolutely guaranteeing you 100% that
it's this way no it's not this way okay
let's try this way ha I knew here we go
in the right way this is the neurotoxin
generator bit bigger than I expected not
going to be able to just you know push
it over
have to apply some cleverness there's
some sort of control room up at the top
so let's go and investigate yeah
there's our handiwork I shouldn't laugh
really they do feel pain of a sort it's
all simulated you know but really enough
for them I suppose
I'm afraid the doors locked just checked
it no way to hack it as far as I can
tell
mechanism us oh that's a big laser
probably best to ignore it though just
leave it be we don't know where those
panels it's cutting are going could be
somewhere important although does give
me an idea what if we stand here and let
the gentle hum of the laser transport us
to a state of absolute relaxation might
help us think of a way to open the door
it's not much of a plan if I'm honest
but I'm afraid it's all we got in this
point barring a sudden barrage of speech
from your direction improbable at best
all right so silent contemplation it is
ste Rios button sorry sorry silence
speak in the silence let the silence
descend here it comes
100% silence from now by the way if you
come up with any ideas do flag of up
don't feel you've got to stay quiet
because I've said absolute silence so if
you come up with an idea mention it but
otherwise absolute silence
starting now let's see what's inside
good news I can use this equipment to
shut down the neurotoxin system it is
however password-protected ah alarm
bells no don't worry
alright not a problem for me you may as
well have a little rest actually while I
work on it okay here we go the hardest
part of any hack is the figuring out how
to start phase that's always tricky but
I'll let the games begin
alright what have we got a computer not
a surprise to be expected to be honest
check that off the list computer
identified tick there is a box part here
probably up some electronics in there
and a monitor yes
that will be important I imagine I'll
keep my eye on that case something
useful comes up important words like
password identified or something like
that and there's a flat bit not sure
where that is but noted anyone says to
me is there a flat bit yes there it is
spinning thing not sure the floor what's
the floor doing oh it's the floor up -
do you know what it's holding everything
up holding everything up the floor is
important holding everything up
pens might need those don't see any
though so if we start making a list of
things that aren't here we could be here
all night
you know pens for instance so let's
stick with things we can see not not
stuff it isn't here all right
preparing to interface with the
neurotoxin central control circuit begin
a leg of neurotoxin inspector need to
shut this place down for a moment
here's my credentials shut yourself down
I have totally legit from the Board of
International neurotoxin observers from
the United Arab Emirates hello
nothing it's he's good this one is good
I'm gonna need to break out the expert
level hacking maneuvers now all right
you asked for it mate love you have a
look at that gorgeous plumage majestic
look over there will be your log that
lovely bird let that happy off
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity this to
see I'm a lovely bird with loving
plumage be a shame to miss it wouldn't
it just for the old neurotoxin
neurotoxin will still be here tomorrow
where's that bird it's gonna be gone any
minute it's already got one Talon off
the branch give me God oh it's flowering
its wings I'll tell you what mate I'll
come in there for a minute
and cover you so that you could have a
look at this lovely bird all right so
I'll come in I'll deal with all the
neurotoxin staff and then you come out
here and look at this because it is
lovely it is lovely you wallet you wanna
get out fast seriously because all of
this my pleasure sounds are gonna fry it
away 80 seconds that ice not working
there isn't it he's not interested in
bloody Birds you smell the Euro toxin
hold up the neurotoxic levels are going
down so whatever you're doing keep doing
it hold on Sonic's wrong neurotoxin
levels up to 50% no it's tagged sorry my
mistake it seems dying 50% it's good
news carry on it's still going down
still going to keep it up
that did it neurotoxin at 0% yes hold on
huh
the tubes broken we can write it
straight to her I can't hold on come on
come on we have to go hurry get in get
in yeah they should take us right to her
I can't believe I'm finally doing this
whoa I knew this would be fun they told
me it wasn't fun at all they say it's
not fun at all I mean I believed I was a
fool to myself this whale of a time this
place is huge
I'm already seeing the top layer it goes
down from miles all sealed-off years ago
of course we should be getting close oh
I can't wait to see the look on her face
no neurotoxin no turrets she'll never
know what hit her
hold on hold on because I might not have
thought this next part completely
through I'm going the wrong way
get to her I'll find you hello oh that's
me they're talking about oh god I did do
what it says to plug me in no you should
plug that little idiot into the
mainframe yes do do it don't listen to
her do it do it come on stop my heroine
plug me in like me and plug me in I want
to be plugged in please
oh we're so close plug me in Oh what can
we do with me then I know plug me into
the pour please all that port looks
comfy what do you put me on it please
dare it dare to dream
shoot for the stars yes oh yes she is
pull me up pull me out pull me out pull
me up pull me up pull me up pull me up
pull me out pull me out pour me out
leave me in leave me in link up brick go
press it yes do do it I think she's
lying okay don't listen to her alright
it is true that you don't have the
qualifications but you've got something
far more important than their a finger
alright with which to press that button
so that she won't kill us okay oh that's
probably correct but where it's
incorrect is that while I've been
stalling you we just press the button
use a moment of confusion I've just
craved to press the button have I let me
just I don't know if I've ever taken the
time to do this but have I ever told you
the qualities that I love most in you in
order number one resolving things love
the way you resolve things particularly
disputes a number one also tied
button-pushing two things I love about
you button pushing and the ability to
resolve things she
disputes first thing I thought about you
when I saw you I thought now there is a
lady who could resolve any button based
disputes if they should arise a diamond
in the rough if you will a bloody
natural a born dispute resolution
advisor in need of a button okay here's
a good idea
you should definitely press that button
sorry to interject again but if you do
not push the button the deadly
neurotoxin emitters will come back
online at which point she will most
likely fill you to brimming with
neurotoxin Russia just throwing that out
there for leisurely digestion in your
own time here we go wait what if this
hurts wife this really hurts
I didn't think of that are you are you
just saying that or is it really gonna
hurt you're just saying there aren't you
you're just no you're not you are is
gonna hurt isn't it exactly how we did
it I'm in control of the whole facility
now Oh would you look at this
not too bad a giant robot massive it's
not just me right
I am bloody massive aren't I oh right
yeah the escape lift I'll call it now
there we go
lift called look how small you are down
there I could barely see you very tiny
and insignificant wait I've just thought
of something how am I gonna get in you
know being bloody massive and everything
wait I know you get into the lift okay
then I'll eject myself out of my new
body into the lift just as you passed by
me brilliant it's perfect except for the
glass hitting us when I smash through
the lift that's a bit of a problem also
once I inject myself out of the core the
lift might stop then we'd be trapped in
a lift full of broken glass suspended 50
feet off the ground you know what just
gained the lift and will iron out the
details as we go come on Caine get in
the lift the escape lift just there come
on the one you risked your life to get
to so you can escape certain death no
rush um it's the lift just there if the
thing that looks like a lift that's what
you're looking for it is confusing I
know it'll be fine get in let me tell
you I knew it was gonna be cool to be in
charge of everything but wow this is
cool and check this out I'm a bloody
genius now it's not some toys for
software they punish only for non
correct are you pay in my wallet I don't
even know what I just said but I can
find out oh sorry no the lift yes sorry
I keep forgetting this body's amazing
seriously I can't go over how small you
are behind huge
actually why do we have to leave right
now do you have any idea how good this
feels I did this tiny little Wheatley
did this oh really
that's what the two of you think is it
well maybe it's time I did something
then and don't think I'm not onto you
too lady you know what you are selfish
I've done nothing but sacrifice to
cutters here and what have you
sacrificed nothing zero all you've done
is boss me around while now who's the
boss who's the boss ah see that that is
a potato battery it's a toy for children
and now she lives in it
so uh what no not listening not
listening no no you're lying you're
lying I am NOT a moron well how about
now
now who's a moron could a moron punch
you into this pit ah good amoral do that
oh for God's sake your boxes with legs
it's yet literally your only purpose
walking on two buns how can you not do
the one thing you're designed for warmer
warmer boiling hot boy
okay colder colder ice cold your Arctic
that is yep you're very cold very very
very cold look just get on the button oh
that's fun easy oh he's funny because
we've been at this for 12 hours and you
haven't sold either so no why you're
laughing you've got one hour solve it hi
yes
I knew you'd solve it oh hello um true
I'll go true yeah that was easy I'll be
honest I'm I've heard that one before
though sort of cheating ah false
I'll go false hold on I thought I fixed
that they're fixed Hey
it is great seeing you guys again
seriously it turns out I'm a little bit
short on test subjects right now so this
works out perfect and off we go and off
we go
alright get moving move you have no idea
what it's like in this body I have to
test all the time or I get this this
itch you know it must be hard wired into
the sister
or something oh but I tell you when I do
test
oh man alive nothing feels better it's
just I got a test so I've got a test so
you're gonna test and I'm gonna watch
and everything is gonna be just fine
shall I designed this test myself it's a
little bit difficult you'll notice the
motor area there very deadly extremely
dangerous eventually it's not at the
moment but I'm working on it still
working on it impossible as it is to
imagine there actually is a solution
devilishly hidden I'll give you a hint
button that's all I'm gonna say one word
button go on come on solve it solve it
solve it commanding voice oh yes oh well
then that's tremendous
yeah you're not done yet are you still
gotta get through the door need to get
through the door there still go still
gonna get through the door please
through that you need to get through
that door there door finish it oh that
felt really good
oh here's an idea since making tests is
so difficult why don't you just keep
solving this test same one and I can
just like what you solve it yeah but
that sounds much easier here we go
now do it again go on come on you've
already solved it come on you've already
solved it once less than a minute ago
you solve this puzzle do it again please
one minute go let less than one minute
ago you solve this puzzle now you're
having problems you just beat this test
literally 20 seconds ago button
press the button the button press the
button mmm nothing all right can't blame
me for trying okay new tests new tests
gotta be some tests around here
somewhere oh here we go it's all right
everything's good I just invented some
more tests not entirely not entirely
look at the word test there on the wall
that's brand new oh well done seriously
both of you why do i why don't you two
go on ahead yeah I'll just I'll catch up
with you ah bless your little primate
brain I'm actually the roux with you oh
my technology it's complicated you can't
hurt the big
old God face do you know what I've got
too many of around ear monitors I was
actually thinking earlier today I got I
wish I had fewer monitors that were
working so you're just helping me really
by smashing him okay
to clarify I was being little bit
facetious about that wanting to get rid
of monitors thing they are actually
really quite useful so I do what their
own so if you could just avoid smashing
them yes all right okay this is getting
tiresome I'm surprised you haven't got
something better to do
to be honest I know I have but you what
he done you've proven that you could
break screens it's proven well done
factual well done good
aren't you Little Miss clever little
miss smushy smash sorry does it actually
make you feel good doing that cuz you
know it's not impressive no one's
impressed it's just glass isn't it
fragile anyone could baby could smash
one of them it's not impressive you know
what there are test subjects in Africa
who don't even have monitors in their
test chambers alright why do you think
about that before you break any more of
them yeah what is this like a hobby for
you now I mean honestly it's you know
it's crazy I mean I mean you must you've
been running around for hours I'm
surprised you've got the energy the
smash screens willy nilly honestly I
thought I'd have a little lie-down if I
were you with an app starting now if I'm
honest ii wonder if you're doing all
this screen breaking on purpose i'm
beginning to actually take it personally
you know the mean like it's like it's
like an insult to me oh there's another
one there's another one they're not
inexpensive but less like to point that
out it seems unfair you know smashing
screens you could give them to people if
you're gonna serve smashing them unscrew
them and give them to like a homeless
person or know what a homeless person
would do with but being at my point it
just seems and you can unscrew a minder
they're bolted in but just stop hear it
yeah just wanted to flag up it's not
like I got hordes of replacement
monitors just lying around back here in
the old where I could just wheel out and
bolt back on didn't didn't order in
loads of spare monitors thinking some
crazy woman's gonna go around smashing
them all sorry if that's my fault sorry
I didn't have the for thoughts I think
all she she might go crazy one day just
smash all the monitors he said just get
on with things that sorry I didn't think
of that they're not even your screens to
break it's vandalism is pure vandalism
you wouldn't do that if this was your
ice would you if you were in if I came
read your ice
smashing you
tell eat a bit you'd be furious and
rightly so unbelievable yeah made this
test myself all smaller tests that I
found lying around jammed him altogether
buttons got funnels bottomless pits are
involved sky little it's got it all
absolute dynamite alright okay this is
taking too long okay I'll just tell you
how to solve the test okay see that
button over there alright never mind
never mind solve it yourself you're on
your own
oh yes well dad don't start yet don't
start yet you're not gonna believe this
I find a sealed-off wing hundreds
hundreds of perfectly good test chambers
just sitting there filled with skeletons
shut them out good as new
and there we go be honest you can't even
tell can you seamless oh here we go
here it comes Oh
disappointed alright so that last test
was seriously disappointing apparently
being civil isn't motivating you so
let's well let's try her way alright
fratty adopted fatty fatty fatty no
parents what what what's wrong with
being adopted aunt well um lack of
parents number one so and also nothing
but some of my best friends actually are
orphans but just do the test just do the
test it's not enough if I'm such a moron
why can't you solve a simple test oh
sorry sorry sorry I hope that isn't but
they didn't disturb you too much then it
was the sound of books pages being
turned sighs just what I was doing just
reading books so not immoral anyway just
finish the last one just no the hardest
one Machiavelli do not know what all the
fuss was about understood it perfectly
have you read that one yeah don't it
well on the test wish there was more
books who are there's no nothing
there's nothing don't mind me just
moving the old test chamber in a bit
closer to me a default maybe proximity
to the test solving might give us
stronger results what was that hope so I
could have swore you said something
makes me that time oh you assault you
assault sorry nevermind Carol my fault
are you are you absolutely sure you're
solving these correctly I mean yes you
solved it but I'm wondering if maybe
there's a number of ways to solve them
and you pick in all the worst ways no no
that was the solution what my missing
calibrate wave I'm gonna tape you
solving these and then watch ten at once
get a more sort of concentrated burst of
science on a related note I am going to
need you to solve these ten times as
fast anyway just give me a wave would
you before you solve this one all right
I don't want to spoil the ending for
when I watch it later
ow you just solved it in you I told you
to tell to tell me before why are you
making this so hard for me was was
self-destructing already fixed
programmed in one last tremor for all
time sake too I'm one or two more
tremors in there just for fun I'll an
keep his job I'm not a monster
ignore what he's saying then just keep
on testing all right still nothing let's
keep moving sorry about the lift it's
out of service
cuz it melted might as well you know
give you the tour to your left
you'll see some lights of some kind
don't what they do but very science-y
anyway and to your right something huge
hurtling to what god rather that's not
supposed to be there are you all right
back there
here I'll turn the beam off for that ah
I didn't why I thought that would help
but you're alive
great yeah just getting a test ready for
you obviously who else would I be doing
it for no one so let's see here exit
exit exit there is no exit not from I'll
just I'll make an exit before your test
there Bing good perfect on you go I'll
be honest after you told me to turn that
beam off I thought I had lost you went
poking around for other test subjects no
luck there everyone's still dead oh I
did find something though reminds me
I've got a big surprise for you too
seriously
look forward to it you two are gonna
love this big surprise in fact you might
say you're going to love it to death I'm
gonna love it until you did until it
kills you till you're dead all right I
don't know whether you're uh you're
picking up on what I'm saying there but
sorry sorry my fault butterfingers
carry on only three more chambers to you
big surprise siren oh we solved it good
good one good for you I'll bet you're
both dying to know what your big
surprise is well only two more chambers
surprise we're doing it now you've
probably figured it out by now but I
don't need you anymore
I found two little robots back here
built specifically for testing hello
this is the part where I kill you had a
bit of a brainwave
there I was smashing some steel plates
together and I thought to myself yeah
he's deadly
boss missing what's missing and I
thought lots of sharp bits welded onto
the flat bits it's still a work in
progress
don't judge me yet but you know
eventually I'd like to get them to sort
of shoot fire at you moments before
crushing you
that's the so that's where I'm aiming
for but you know small steps oh and
don't bother trying to portal out of
here because it's impossible okay I've
thought of everything
what you're wrong
really and do what exactly
no no stand right here it's that start
machine start machine it's not the
machine where'd you go come back come
back oh you came back I didn't oh I
didn't plan for this
uh can't reset the death trap um Oh
could you just jump into that pit would
you just jump into that pit for me would
you just jump into that pit there that
deadly pit you saying to yourself why
should I jump in the pit I'll tell you
why guess who's down there your parents
you're not adopted after all it's your
natural parents down there in the pit
should have mentioned it before but I
didn't so jump on down and reunite with
mommy and daddy oh I see what's also
down there to your parents and there's
also an escape elevator down there funny
I should've mentioned before but sit
down I said pop die jump down you got
your folks down there and an escape
elevator and what else is down there
tell you what it's only a new jumpsuit a
very trendy designer jumped from France
down there which is at least exactly
your size and if it's a bit baggy was
that we got Taylor down there as well
who can take it in for you what's this a
lovely handbag and the three portals of
also it's so down there you've got yacht
and boys loads of boys fellas hunky guys
down there possibly even a boyfriend
who's to say I'm not sure at this stage
but a lot of good-looking fellas down
there and a boy band as well that
haven't seen a woman in years and
they're not picking at all they don't
care if you've got a bit of brain damage
if you've been running around if you've
been sweating and farm a pony farm and
uh-oh
just jump down would ya oh good I didn't
think that was gonna work no seriously
do come back please come back please
okay look I've decided I'm not gonna
kill you okay if you come back oh just
thinking back to the old times the old
days when we were friends good old
friends not enemies and I would say
something like come back and you'd be
like yeah no problem and you'd come back
what happened to those days can't help
but notice that you're not coming back
which is disappointing oh I've got an
idea yes yes shave your face I got fine
let the games begin
hold on hold on hold on I'm almost there
ah don't mind me continue escaping that
death trap
are they killing you they are killing
you aren't they silently killing you
probably try to guess perhaps the
turrets have found a way to use graz
that would explain the extremely quiet
killing that I'm hearing if you're dying
but not dead
stomp once if you're dead just obviously
no stomps and two stomps if you're not
dead alright so let me run through it
again if you're dying but not dead stop
just once if you're dead obviously you
won't be stomping and if you're not dead
give me a couple of stops two stomps you
know I would tell you if I was dead
alright that is common courtesy mark of
a civil society so just just let me know
okay I'm figuring this probably long
enough are you dead yet how about now ah
was that your bullet-riddled body flying
out the room it what oh those were the
crap turrets weren't they
yeah well no matter because I'm still
holding
all the cards and guess what they're all
full houses never actually played cards
meaning to learn anyway new turrets not
defective ASA fours the best hand
unbeatable
I would imagine oh I see clever very
clever and foolish no way act you're at
my mercy and I don't have any you're at
my nothing
spinny blade wall Machiavellian no well
good good
finally a nemesis worthy of my vast
intellect no wait come back up sorry
please no I was going I was going
somewhere with all that fool you were a
fool to come back because I've trapped
you again helpless you're at my mercy
and I don't have any
you're at my nothing you're at mine but
you're at my lack of mercy and again not
playing along you're ruining or are some
really good speeches actually didn't
even get to the good part yet twist
ending so twisty you might even call it
spinning don't ignore the laughter you
know what nothing to worry about the
puppet master you're a puppet in a play
and I hold all the strings and cards
still still got the card got the cards
in one hand and I got the strings in the
other hand and I'm making you dance like
a puppet playing cards
alright fine I'm not saying another word
till you do it properly I'm sick of this
Holmes versus Moriarty Aristotle versus
masse spiked plates stay still please
alright stop moving almost caught you
there I was going you there where'd you
go where'd you go come back come back
did something break back there oh all
did it kill you that would be amazing if
it killed you hello oh yes I know just a
brainwave I'll be back if you're still
alive I'm gonna be back don't die until
I get back ah there you are
great let me just get rid of this
catwalk there we go I wanted to talk to
you for a moment if I may I'll be honest
the death traps have been a bit of a
failure so far for both of us I think
you'll agree and you are getting very
close to my lair lair weird in that
first offset out loud sounds a bit it
sounds a bit ridiculous really but I can
assure you it is what is a proper lair
deadly lair and I just wanted to give
you the chance to kill yourself now
before you get to the lair you just jump
into that masher just there that's a
death trap or a death option for you
sounds crazy I know but hear me out hear
me out once you get to my lair death
will not be optional or it will be
mandatory no tricks no surprises just
you dying as a result of me killing you
in a very very gruesome way so boom
better offer here is just kill yourself
you know a lot of effort isn't walking
all the way to my deadly lair where
there's a perfectly serviceable death
option right there again not a death
trap not a death trap your death would
be entirely voluntary and very much
appreciated the masher does work I
should point out as well know we've had
a couple of problems in the past they
smash two deadly works and it will kill
you if that's one of your concerns about
not jumping in the master will kill you
straight away painless but it won't be
painless obviously but it will it will
mash you up
in summary walk all the way to certain
doom or give up now
honorably like a samurai save yourself a
trip it's a win-win for you
plus I have put a lot of effort in
getting this lair ready for you so it
would certainly teach me a lesson if you
simply died painlessly 20 feet from the
door I'd be furious I've got my just
desserts
no more than I deserve but teach why not
teach me a lesson by just jumping in the
old masher I tell you if I was having a
shitty possible odds this is the word
wanna go mashed with dignity that would
be the way I choose and here's the best
part there's a conveyor belt that will
convey you inconvenient comfort right
into the masher you would have to lift a
finger everything taken care of didn't
have to didn't have to do that look
anyway smoke enough take your time I'll
let you think about it and I don't want
to pressure you is it the Larry's at the
masher
alright you know what my opinion is
master I'm leaning towards master up to
you just gonna give you some time to
think okay I'll take that as a no then
fight well may the best man win fear may
the best sphere win swap that swap that
in much more clever books okay I'll take
that as a no then well well well
welcome to morning
let me just flag something up according
to the control panel light up there the
entire building is gonna self-destruct
in about six minutes I'm pretty sure
it's a problem with the light I think
the lights on the blink but just in case
it isn't I am actually gonna have to
kill you as discussed earlier so let's
call that three minutes and then a
minute break where we should leave
allegedly two minutes to figure out how
to shut down whatever is starting all
the fires so anyway that's the itinerary
also I took the liberty of watching the
tapes of you killing her and I'm not
gonna make the same mistakes four-part
plan is this one no portal surfaces to
start the neurotoxin immediately three
bomb-proof shields for me leading
directly onto number four bombs for
throwing at you do you know what this
plan is so good I'm gonna give you a
sporting chance and turn off the
neurotoxin I'm joking of course
goodbye where are you going don't run
don't run I tell you I should run the
harder you breathe the more neurotoxin
you inhale it's bloody clever this stuff
seriously it's devilish still running
alright looks tiring tell you what you
stop running and I'll stop bombing you
that seems fair
alright you didn't go for that I see you
I was like point to you but you still
are inhaling neurotoxin so point
deducted look out I'm right behind you
no of course I'm not no you saw through
that one as well
forty feet tall right in front of you
not my greatest ruse to be honest still
giant robot though look at that oh where
are you going
no we're not going anywhere alright got
you trapped like a little jump suited
rat oh did you bring a little portal gun
there's nothing to port long to err love
just ten pounds of dead weight about to
be 210 fatty you're just delaying the
inevitable
alright you cannot run from my bombs
forever well you can if I keep aiming
them poorly but I'll get better as we go
and you'll just get tired this would go
a lot faster if you'd stay still then
I've have time to fix the facility so
one of us at least would live there's no
need to be selfish love you're gonna die
I should congratulate you by the way I
didn't actually think you would make
such a worthy opponent what are you
supposed to be brain damaged or
something yeah brain damaged like a fox
remember when I first told you how to
find that little portal thing you love
so much
well I thought you died on the way if
I'm honest all the others did you didn't
think you were the first did you
hahaha no no
fifth no I like six perhaps it's best to
leave it to your imagination what
happened to the other five do you know
what I think we're well past the point
of tasteful restraint so I'll tell you
happened to them they died horrific ly
they all died horrific ly trying to get
to that portal device that you're
gripping in your meaty little fingers
there oh but you were different weren't
you you were such a good jumper
problem-solver Oh clever but ambitious
you see ambitious that's your Achilles
heel
mine's Oh Oh almost told you clever
clever girl again brain damaged like a
fox you we've had some times haven't we
like that time I jumped off my
management rail not sure if I died or
not when I did and all you had to do is
catch me and you didn't did you
oh you remember that I remember that I
remember that all the time and we could
have talked our way out of it except you
forgot to tell me that you'd murdered
her and that she needed you to live so
the only available event for her age
would be good old crushable Wheatley
yeah
little details that I remember easy
little tidbits you could have used to
save me from getting crushed if you'd
cared wish you didn't obviously and
still do not Oh remember the time I took
over the facility greatest moment of my
life but you just wanted to leave didn't
want to share my success well so you
know I would be happy for you if you
succeeded
apart from right now obviously am I
being too vague I despise you I love you
you arrogant smugly quiet awful jump
suited monster of a woman you and your
little potato friend this place would
have been a triumph if it wasn't for you
oh that's sounded real no that was
actually an impression of you actually
because you just fell into my trap my
brilliant trap just then I wanted you to
trick me into bursting that pipe didn't
trick didn't trick me seemingly trick me
to give you false hope because that
leads to overconfidence and that leads
to mistakes fatal mistakes it's all part
of a plan
ah but haha i jus actually made my
actual first mistake by telling you my
plan just now ah it's me old Achilles
heel again and armed with that knowledge
I imagine you won't even use the
conversion gel ah fate are cruel
mistress that conversion gel has been
sitting in that pipe going stagnant for
year you probably get botulism toward
portaling through it like that and
you'll probably get ringworm and
athlete's foot and cholera or something
horrible it's gonna be even worse than
if I just blown you up but it's not too
late to avoid all of that by simply not
using the gel just stop using that I
said it there you are I said it I gave
you it gave you a game away my plan but
I just I couldn't watch you hurt
yourself like this ah what what happened
what happened what why have you what you
pawned to me why is that hold on are the
bloody bombs are stuck on doesn't matter
I've reconfigured the shields
oh I said core you've pawed me who told
you to do that was it her it's just
making me stronger love it's a fool's
errand are you trying to weigh me down
do you think I'll fall out of the
ceiling well work I'm not just quite
brilliant I'm also quite strong biggest
muscle in my body my brain second
biggest my muscles so it's not gonna
work clearly did you plant virus in them
okay but it's not gonna work either or I
can I've got a firewall mate literally
actually that know that I look a rat
that there appears to literally be a
wall of fire around this place that's
quite it's alarming to say the least
in fact I've got to take a break for a
minute up a partial break during which
I'll stop the facility from exploding
wall still throwing bombs at you all
right then let's let's see vital
maintenance protocols wow there's a lot
of them should have looked into this
earlier well let's try this do them
they're enough maybe maybe it's a
password
ay-ay-ay-ay-ay
no okay ay-ay-ay-ay-ay done both of
these skip it skip ahead a B C D G H
bloody worked I hacked I hacked it
hacked it back probably hacked now then
let's see let's see what we got here
oh reactor core emergency heat venting
protocols that's the problem right there
isn't it emergency you don't wanna see
emergency flashing out here never good
that is it never good right delete and
delete underneath where's the under
leapin enough I told you not to put
these cores on me but you don't listen
do you quiet all the time
quietly not listening to a word I say
judging me silently the worst kind all I
wanted to do was make everything better
from me all you had to do was to solve a
couple of hundred simple tests for a few
years and you couldn't even let me have
that
could you nobody's going to space mate
and another thing you never caught me I
told you I could die falling off that
rail you didn't catch me didn't even try
oh it's all becoming clear to me now
find some Joop to break your cryo sleep
give him some sob story about escaping
to the surface squeeze him for
information on where to find a portal
gun then when he's but he's no more you
see you he has a little accident doesn't
he fools of his management rail doesn't
he here in this together aren't you
you've been playing me the whole time
both of you first you made me think
you're brain damage then you convinced
me your sworn enemies with your best
friend over here then then when I
reluctantly assume the responsibility of
running the place you conveniently
decide to run off together just what I
need you the most I'll bet there isn't
even a problem with the facility is
there I bet there's no such thing as a
reactor core okay that's not even fire
coming out of the walls is it
it's just cleverly placed lights and
papier-mache a parasol is all those
pieces of the ceiling that keep falling
out probably probably actual pieces of
the ceiling I bet they look real but
doesn't signify anything is my point but
the real point oh you know I just
remembered football
kicking a ball around for fun cruel
obviously humans love it now for shoulda
seen it coming you have been a thorn in
my side long enough oh I see
what do you think no no no no no no
didn't pick up on my sarcasm ah that
just cleans right off does it well that
would have been good to know a little
earlier no no do not press that button
do not do it I forbid you to press it do
not press that button do not press that
button do not do it don't press that
button come back don't press it come
back part 5 booby trap this stalemate
button what are you still alive you are
joking you have got to be kidding me
well I'm still in control and I have no
idea how to fix this place oh you had to
play bloody cat and Maxton you what
people were trying to work yeah well now
we're all gonna pay the price
cuz we're all gonna bloody die Oh
brilliant yeah take one more look at
your precious human moon cuz it cannot
help you now
space let go we're in space let go let
go I'm still connected I can pull myself
in I can still fix this
oh no change of plans hold on to me
tighter Oh grab me grab me grab me grab
me it makes peace maybe see yeah I wish
I could take it all back I honestly do I
honestly do wish I could take it all
back and not just cuz I'm stranded in
space anything I know who you are mate
yeah we're both in space anyway you know
if I was ever to see her again do you
know what I'd say anything I'd say I'm
sorry sincerely I are sorry I was bossy
and monstrous and I am genuinely sorry
in each case the end